This glacier is bleeding, and they just
found something very weird inside. This
is Bloodfalls, right here in Antarctica.
If you followed it in, you'd find an
ancient lake full of tons of microbes
that eat rocks, specifically these rocks
that the bedrock grinds up as this
glacier moves across it. And then, they
poop out iron. So, when this iron water
reaches the surface, it rusts. That's
the red [music] color. But now, they
found new single-celled marine organisms
on the surface, which is weird because
the ocean is over 30 km away and not
connected, meaning these must be
connected to ancient marine life. But
when they went deeper down into the ice
in Antarctica, they found something even
crazier. To see that, subscribe.